<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>λ lisps and UNIXisms</title>
    <link>https://defphil.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on λ lisps and UNIXisms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 12:10:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://defphil.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OS Threading 101</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/blog/os-threading-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 12:10:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/blog/os-threading-101/</guid>
      <description>Thread creation and initialization illumos might not be the happiest place to start with learning about multithreaded handling and implementation on OS level simply because of complexity of system. It carries a lot of &#39;legacy&#39; code from Solaris and SPARC architecture and includes systems like Zones and Dtrace which may lead to confussion, but we will focus on it&#39;s source code that is applicable to x86 platform.
(illumos/usr/src/uts/common/disp/thread.c)
Thread structure and organization As we know on x86 stack grows down (on Solaris it&#39;s selectable for example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker manifesto</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/code/</guid>
      <description>A manifesto is a published verbal declaration of the intentions, motives, or views of the issuer, be it an individual, group, political party or government. A manifesto usually accepts a previously published opinion or public consensus or promotes a new idea with prescriptive notions for carrying out changes the author believes should be made. It often is artistic or political in nature, but may present an individual&#39;s life stance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/home/</guid>
      <description>Filip Miletic  github sr.ht best to reach me via email you can also find me on lobste.rs or as phlm on Freenode</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lispomania</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/blog/lispomania/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/blog/lispomania/</guid>
      <description>Finding zen in parentheses Pretty early in my life I decided I wanted to be an engineer. A little bit later I discovered writing software can be really fun and I ejoyed it. Then I found out it pays really well. But I always asked myself is that enough to be happy? What does it mean to be happy anyway? On faculty I saw a lot of people that got into CS because &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I also love art, reading, listening to music and DJing, riding skate and hanging out in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>