<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>λ personal website</title>
    <link>https://defphil.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on λ personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 14:08:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://defphil.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax highlighting and other fluff</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/blog/syntax-highlighting-and-other-fluff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 14:08:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/blog/syntax-highlighting-and-other-fluff/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been programming for little over 5 years now, and I&#39;ve always been obsesed with how my terminals, editors, tiling WMs (ah, the Linux and *BSD days) and other stuff that you productively waste time on. Automate whole setup with multiple bash and Ansible scripts, so you crash your system and get everything up and runing with running single file. Yea, high school was blast! But as I got into faculty time became more and more precious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker manifesto</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/code/</guid>
      <description>A manifesto is a published verbal declaration of the intentions, motives, or views of the issuer, be it an individual, group, political party or government. A manifesto usually accepts a previously published opinion or public consensus or promotes a new idea with prescriptive notions for carrying out changes the author believes should be made. It often is artistic or political in nature, but may present an individual&#39;s life stance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/home/</guid>
      <description>Filip Miletic  githubsr.ht mail: phlm [at] protonmail.com you can also find me on lobste.rs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lispomania</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/blog/lispomania/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/blog/lispomania/</guid>
      <description>Finding zen in parentheses Pretty early in my life I decided I wanted to be an engineer. A little bit later I discovered writing software can be really fun and I ejoyed it. Then I found out it pays really well. But I always asked myself is that enough to be happy? What does it mean to be happy anyway? On faculty I saw a lot of people that got into CS because &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/blog/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 03:01:38 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/blog/test/</guid>
      <description>I recently read Greg Hendershott&#39;s emacs themes blog post, and cribbed liberally from his approach to loading themes. I also cribbed his Hydra theme switcher. It was so fun to use! I wanted to try it with all the themes I have installed---but I didn&#39;t want to add all of them manually. Boo! So I set out to see if I could dynamically add all installed themes to my Hydra theme switcher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>https://defphil.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://defphil.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I also love art, reading, listening to music and DJing, riding skate and hanging out in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>