<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying Rusty</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/staying-rusty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/staying-rusty/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve ordered a copy of the book by Steve Klabnik and Carol Nichols &#39;The Rust Programming Language&#39;. I was following development of Rust for last two years, reading various blogs and posts by it&#39;s community members, and decided that this is the year when I will get my feet wet in Rust. Before this I was writing fair amount of C, and was familiar with programming in C++ and Assembly. As I was EE major I was exposed to various lower levels of logic and programming and I liked it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type system pendulum</title>
      <link>/post/2018/06/29/type-system-pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/06/29/type-system-pendulum/</guid>
      <description>A little bit of history During last 10 to 15 years we saw rise in popularity of dynamically typed languages. Developers delved from statically typed era of Java into web stacks written in dynamically typed languages like PHP/Ruby/JS/Python. That impacted popularity of typed programming languages the most . But as we are moving down the timeline towards today, we can see pendulum swinging back to statical typing systems but in some weird way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual domain nature of Computer Science</title>
      <link>/post/2018/05/04/dual-domain-nature-of-computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/05/04/dual-domain-nature-of-computer-science/</guid>
      <description>Learning struggles Today, on my way home I was listening to CaSE podcast, who&#39;s guest was none other than Rich Hickey. For the biggest part of podcast he was talking about some really cool technological things that we can expect in near future in Clojure ecosystem. I recommend anyone familiar with Clojure or ClojureScript to listen to this episode, I always like hearing Rich talk. But the meatiest part that got me thinking was near the end, probably last twenty minutes of this episode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects vs Lambdas</title>
      <link>/post/2018/04/20/objects-vs-lambdas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/04/20/objects-vs-lambdas/</guid>
      <description>Change of perception This won&#39;t be another &#34;Oh my god, SICP changed my life and the way I look at software&#34; blog post. Although it did certainly have significant impact on my perception on how to write software, but I want to talk about something a little bit different today; how functional programming changed the way I write Object Oriented code.
It&#39;s rather easy to get caught up in pitfalls of object oriented programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstraction contraction</title>
      <link>/post/2018/04/17/abstraction-contraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/04/17/abstraction-contraction/</guid>
      <description>Software and it&#39;s weird nature The most exciting and weird thing I found out about in early teenage days was software. I started my journey with TurboPASCAL on start of my second year of high school. It felt really weird at first, mostly because I kinda expected from computers to be magically less stupid than they actually were. &#34;What? I have to tell them when I am about to use natural number, wtf?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gonzo Science</title>
      <link>/post/2018/03/21/gonzo-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/03/21/gonzo-science/</guid>
      <description>Seeing the white rabbit Yesterday I&#39;ve finished reading What the Dormouse Said and The Soul of a New Machine. First I have to make a confession. I always had weak spot for 60s in America. It is such distant place for me, both geographically and by time, but it always impressed me and inspired me, don&#39;t know why. I was hooked up on Rock &#39;n&#39; Roll when I was a kid, it was influence from my uncle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>